Taral Shah

TeleMedicine Engineer | Healthcare Data Enthusiast

+1 289 380 7672

in taral-shah-87215163

staral81291@hotmail.com

TeleMedicine Engineer with 6 years of hands-on experience dealing with **Clinical Informatics and healthcare Data**.

Microsoft Professional Certificate in Data Science and support on various cardiology and radiology products.

Healthcare **Data Analysis** using Power BI, Azure ML and Various Python libraries.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Healthcare Data Enthusiast

Toronto, CA, 2019 - Present

Researches, extracts and manipulates complex (open) data from various sources. Perform ETL using various Python Libraries. Identifies and understands new and emerging patterns. Develop Reports and Dashboards using data visualization tools such as Power BI, Tableau, Splunk etc. Machine learning models design using Python libraries like scikit-learn, TensorFlow etc. Design and deploy models using Azure Machine Learning Studio.

Telemedicine Engineer

CompuMed Inc., Toronto, CA, Jan 2018 - Present

Converted, cleaned and analyzed medium-large data files to Developed report processes using SQL and Python. Playing key role in development of improved processing workflows for decreased operating costs. Building reports, dashboards and data visualizations that are used everyday by team leads and executives using Power BI. Primary technical point of contact for Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve Issues related to Medical equipment and PACS/RIS Platforms. Evaluate the safety, efficiency, and effectiveness of PACS Platform using various analysis techniques. Design and integration of EHR Platform and related data flows. Test / Evaluate and support the roll-out of new technology. Train clinicians, nurses and other healthcare personnel on the proper use of PACS and EHR Software.

Biomedical Engineer

CompuMed Inc., Los Angeles, USA, May 2014 - Jan 2018

On-site and off-site repair, install, maintenance and calibration of GE, Schiller and Mortara 's cardiology equipment. Act as liaison with technicians and manufacturers to ensure the feasibility of a biomedical software product in terms of design and economic viability. Provide onsite IT Support by monitoring and maintaining desktop, server and network. Troubleshoot system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults and escalate to IT Manager as necessary.

□ SKILLS

Technical

Personal

Python
Power BI
SQL
Azure ML
Tableau
R Language
Google Analytics
MATLAB
EHR
LabVIEW
C#.Net

Problem Solving
Analytical Skills
Creative Thinking
Project Management
Cooperate Training
Rapport Building

HIGHLIGHTS

Business Analytics using Power BI and Python for various level of management

Working on **ML model** to improve turn-around time of **ECG** and **ECHO** using various **python libraries** and **Azure ML**

Experience **Presenting Statistical Findings** various level of management

Partial load Faculty at Durham College, School of Science & Engineering Technology

Biomedical Innovation Award for "Mobile based ECG System" project from Department of Science & Technology, Government of Gujarat (India).

EDUCATION

Microsoft Professional Certificate in Data Science

Microsoft Online, edX, 2017

MS in Biomedical Engineering

Wayne State University, Michigan, USA, 2014

BTE in Biomedical & Instrumentation Engineering

Ganpat University, Gujarat, India, 2011